<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Toni&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://czyrnik.me/</link>
    <description>Toni&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://czyrnik.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Beauty and Wilderness of the Swedish Lapland: My Kungsleden Trek 🥾</title>
      <link>https://czyrnik.me/blog/kungsleden-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://czyrnik.me/blog/kungsleden-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Kungsleden, or &amp;ldquo;King&amp;rsquo;s Trail&amp;rdquo;, is a 400-km trek through Swedish Lapland that attracts hikers and outdoor enthusiasts from around the world. This trail offers a unique experience that combines breathtaking natural beauty, peaceful solitude, and the chance to immerse yourself in the rugged wilderness of the Arctic Circle both in summer and winter. There are STF-operated &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swedishtouristassociation.com/stf-mountain-shops-shop-off-beaten-track/&#34;&gt;mountain huts&lt;/a&gt; every 10 to 20 km. You can buy your food and necessities in their stores. You need to find your trade-off between saving weight and spending more than usual. 🎒&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./map.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Kungsleden Map&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently hiked Kungsleden from south to north and it was an unforgettable experience. My hike started in the small town of Kvikkjokk after a night in Luleå and an early train ride. I started in the middle of June, the beginning of the season. So I avoided the hordes of mosquitoes around Kvikkjokk. 🦟&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./view_laitaure.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Laitaure&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are constantly rewarded with breathtaking views of mountains, crystal clear lakes and dense forests of pine and birch trees. The nature changes significantly during the hike. The south is dominated by a &amp;ldquo;sea of trees&amp;rdquo;, while the north is characterized by rocks and clear views into the distance due to the higher elevation. 🏕️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./skierfe.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;View from the mountain Skierfe&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the highlights of the hike was reaching the top of Skierfe. You can see part of
Sarek National Park from the top. It is the oldest national park in Europe and is known for its rugged and untamed landscapes. The park is home to a wide variety of wildlife, including reindeer, moose and a variety of bird species. 🏔️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beauty of this view was incomparable. I will return to the Sarek in the future. This time, I just spend some time to enjoy the beauty of the north. 👀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./vakkotavare_teusajaure.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Pass between Vakkotavare and Teusajaure&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great experience was camping in the remote wilderness. You are allowed to camp almost everywhere - stay away from buildings. 🏠&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was difficult to find dry places because of all the snow melting in June. Once I found a spot for the night, I felt how disconnected I was from the outside world. 🌱&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The silence was broken only by the sounds of nature, such as the wind rustling through the trees and the occasional bird call. It was the perfect opportunity to reflect, recharge, and connect with the natural world. 🤫&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./near_kaitumjaure.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Kaitumjaure&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I continued north, I met other hikers from all over the world and we shared our experiences, stories, and the conditions ahead. This made the trip even more memorable. 🗣️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./camp_after_tjaktja.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Camp after Tjäktja&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most challenging parts was the mountain pass after Tjäktja. Fellow hikers told me that the pass opened two days before I arrived. There was so much snow! ❄️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every few minutes I would break through the snow, not knowing what is underneath me. Sometimes you hear flowing water and hope the snow will hold. 🥶&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t walk over blueish snow. That&amp;rsquo;s a sign of a thin layer over running water. ⚠️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a rough experience, but eventually I made it to the top and was able to dry my feet. The shelter filled up quickly. But after an hour I left to reach the next place for the night. 🥾&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./tjäktja_pass.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Tjäktja Mountain Pass&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After about a week, I reached the end of the trail in Abisko, where I could take the train back to civilization and reflect on my journey. The Kungsleden had tested my physical and mental limits, but it gave me a sense of peace and accomplishment that I will always cherish. 🚀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;itinerary-overview&#34;&gt;Itinerary Overview
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#itinerary-overview&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 1: 25 km, Kvikkjokk to Parte&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 2: 16 km, Parte to Aktse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 3: 25 km, Aktse to Skierfe to Sitojaure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 4: 16 km, Sitojaure to Saltoluokta&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 5: 20 km, Vakkotavare to Kaitumjaure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 6: 22 km, Kaitumjaura to (almost) Sälka&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 7: 26 km, Sälka to (almost) Alesjaure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 8: 35 km, Alesjaure to Abisko&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total: ~185 km&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lake-crossings&#34;&gt;Lake Crossings
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#lake-crossings&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the key features of the trail are the numerous lake crossings that provide scenic views. The crossings vary in difficulty and length, from short and easy to long and strenuous. The more challenging crossings require the use of boats. You can read more about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swedishtouristassociation.com/boats-in-the-mountains/&#34;&gt;the boats in the mountains&lt;/a&gt;. 🚣&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not underestimate the current &amp;amp; wind on the lake. ⚠️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note that all boat traffic must be paid in cash.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview-south-to-north&#34;&gt;Overview (South to North)
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#overview-south-to-north&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lájtávrre: before Aktse Hut (about 1.5 km to 2 km)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rowing Boats available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gasskajávrre: before Sitojaure Hut&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No&lt;/strong&gt; Rowing Boats available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call to book your boat at the sign on the trek&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Langas: after Saltoluokta Hut&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No&lt;/strong&gt; Rowing Boats available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Buy your boat ticket online or in the reception!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teusajaure: before Teusajaure Hut (1 km)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rowing Boats available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stf-membership&#34;&gt;STF Membership
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#stf-membership&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Swedish Tourist Association (STF) operates and maintains the Kungsleden Trail, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swedishtouristassociation.com/join-stf/&#34;&gt;STF membership&lt;/a&gt; is an option for those who wish to support the maintenance and preservation of the trail. STF members receive discounts on various activities and services related to the trail. 👏&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hiking the Kungsleden from south to north was an amazing experience that I recommend to anyone looking for adventure and a chance to escape the hustle and bustle of everyday life. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re an experienced hiker or looking to challenge yourself, the Kungsleden is a unique and unforgettable journey. 🤓&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Nomad Experience in Riga</title>
      <link>https://czyrnik.me/blog/nomad-riga/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://czyrnik.me/blog/nomad-riga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;welcome-to-the-baltics---riga-edition&#34;&gt;Welcome to the Baltics - Riga Edition
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#welcome-to-the-baltics---riga-edition&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was an easy bus ride between Tallinn and Riga. My Airbnb was near the main railway station, a few minutes walk. Riga felt more chaotic than Tallinn for the first few minutes. There are more people, cars and buses. 🚎&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./city_aerial.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Aerial Shot by Gilly&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;old-town&#34;&gt;Old Town
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#old-town&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Riga&amp;rsquo;s Old Town is a UNESCO World Heritage Site. The cobbled streets are lined with medieval buildings, many of which have been beautifully restored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./old_town.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Old Town Vibes by Jacques Bopp&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the main highlights of the Old Town is the Town Hall Square, which is home to the impressive Riga Town Hall. This Gothic-style building was built in the 14th century and now houses the Riga City Council. The Town Hall Square is surrounded by other notable buildings, such as the House of the Blackheads and the St. Peter&amp;rsquo;s Church. You can take a guided tour of the Town Hall to learn more about its history and architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./townhall.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Town Hall Square by Martin Kleppe&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The St. Peter&amp;rsquo;s Church is one of the largest medieval churches in the Baltic region. Built in the 13th century, it is a mixture of Gothic and Baroque styles. You can take a guided tour of the cathedral to learn more about its history and admire its impressive stained glass windows and frescoes. 🔔&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./cathedral.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;St. Peter&#39;s Church by Artem Makarov&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Old Town is a great place to explore on foot. You can stroll along the cobbled streets and admire the colorful buildings and street art. The Old Town is full of shops, cafes and restaurants where you can enjoy traditional Latvian food and drinks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vegan-community&#34;&gt;Vegan Community
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#vegan-community&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Riga has a thriving vegan community, with several restaurants and cafes catering to this lifestyle. Many of these places offer delicious and healthy food options, such as salads, smoothies, and raw desserts. 💚&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./kozy_eats.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Kozy Eats by Kozy Eats&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it is less common to be vegan in Riga. I cooked a lot during my stay. 👨‍🍳&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;population&#34;&gt;Population
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#population&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the collapse of the Soviet Union in 1991, Latvia regained its independence and began the process of transition to a market economy. This led to significant changes in the demographics of the city&amp;rsquo;s population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 1990s, Riga&amp;rsquo;s population declined due to emigration, mainly of the Russian-speaking population. The city&amp;rsquo;s population fell from around 900,000 in the early 1990s to around 700,000 in the late 1990s. This trend was driven by the economic and political instability in the country during this period and the desire of many Russian-speaking residents to return to their home country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./Riga_plot.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Population Trend in Riga&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city&amp;rsquo;s economy improved and more people moved to the city to work and study. EU accession in 2004 helped to attract more investment and business opportunities to Riga. Outside the city centre, many commercial spaces are unoccupied. Walking through the outer streets can sometimes feel sad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The streets are full of cars, even though the city has lost almost a third of its population. It&amp;rsquo;s always busy in Riga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;public-transport&#34;&gt;Public Transport
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#public-transport&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Riga has a well-developed public transport system that includes buses, trams and trolleybuses. Buses run frequently and can take you to most destinations in Riga. The tram system has several lines running through the city centre and suburbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public transport in Riga is affordable, with a one-way ticket costing around two euros (valid for one hour) and a day ticket costing around four euros (valid for 24 hours).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are travelling by train, you can use the official app (Pasažieru vilciens) to buy your tickets. The stations outside the city can be minimalist though. 😊&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./beach_train.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Train Station near the beach&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;beach&#34;&gt;Beach
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#beach&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Riga&amp;rsquo;s beach is not the most popular among tourists, but it is worth a visit. The beach is located in Jurmala, a coastal town about 30 minutes from the city centre. 🚂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed taking the train from Riga Central Station to one of the stops along the beach. Personally, time on the beach gives me an instant holiday feeling. 🤓&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./beach1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Beach near Riga&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beach is long and wide, with fine white sand and clear blue water. There are many beach bars and restaurants serving delicious food and drinks. It is the perfect place to relax and enjoy the sun and sea. ☀️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./beach2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Beach near Riga&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;parks&#34;&gt;Parks
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#parks&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Riga has several beautiful parks, perfect for a relaxing stroll or a picnic. The largest and most popular park is Mežaparks, located on the banks of the Daugava River. The park has a lake, a playground and several monuments. Another popular park is Esplanade Park, located in the heart of the city, with a music pavilion, fountain and several statues. The park is a great place to relax and enjoy the fresh air. There are many other small parks and gardens throughout the city, such as the Riga Botanical Garden and Ziedoņdārzs Park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./boat_park.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Tourist Boat in Esplanade Park&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to go to the park on hot, sunny days. Combined with a light breeze, it&amp;rsquo;s the perfect summer day in the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./water_park.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Esplanade Park&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Riga is a beautiful and affordable city. My favorite place in Riga was the beach.I&amp;rsquo;d prefer Tallinn to Riga. Although Riga is the bigger city with more opportunities.🙃&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./me.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Me in Riga, June 2022&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote Studying and Working in Tallinn</title>
      <link>https://czyrnik.me/blog/nomad-tallinn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://czyrnik.me/blog/nomad-tallinn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;welcome-to-the-baltics&#34;&gt;Welcome to the Baltics
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#welcome-to-the-baltics&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, I chose Tallinn as the first destination as a digital nomad. Tallinn - the tiny capital many never heard of. I think it&amp;rsquo;s one of the most underrated cities in Europe. 🇪🇺&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estonia is the country with the most digital government in Europe. Their ID cards provide digital access for signatures, voting, medical records and submitting tax claims. You can even start your first business digitally. But there are things you need to do in person: marriage, divorce and a credit for properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;IT education is important in Estonia. All children start learning about algorithms and coding at the age of seven. It&amp;rsquo;s designed to be preparation for the digital age.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./Old town Entrance.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Small Street in Tallinn Old Town by 66 north&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun Fact: When you walk around the city, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice the lokal coffeeshops &amp;ldquo;Reval&amp;rdquo;. That&amp;rsquo;s the original name of the city until 1918. The name changed to Tallinn with the independence of Estonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reval was a significant trade hub in Europe during the 14th and 16th centuries. Today, the old town of Tallinn is one of the best-preserved medieval cities and is classified as a UNESCO World Heritage Site. You get a glimpse of the former medieval fortress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tallinn was occupied by the German until end of World War 1. Followed by the occupation by the Red Army during World War 2 in 1940. Nazi Germany occupied the city from 1941 to 1944. But Soviet occupation was quickly reestablished until 1991. Tallinn became the capital of an independent country once again in August 1991. 🎉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;population&#34;&gt;Population
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#population&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tallinn experienced an extensive influx of Russian immigrants during the Soviet occupation (1944-1991). Whole new city districts were developed like Lasnamäe,T which became the most populous district of Tallinn in the 1980s. &lt;em&gt;Today, about 50 % of the inhabits speak Estonian and about 46 % speak Russian as their native language.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./plot.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Inhabitants in Estonia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;old-town&#34;&gt;Old Town
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#old-town&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was lucky to live in the middle of the city. My apartment was next to the town hall square. Many tourists arrive by ferry and bus for day trips. Consequently, the streets can get crowded. But the early mornings and late nights are comparatively quiet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./Old town.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Small streets in Old Town by 
Nikola Johnny Mirkovic&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the Russian embassy was always guarded by at least one Estonian police car. Estonias do support the Ukrainians in the war. 🇺🇦&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./embassy.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Posters in front of the Russian embassy&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old Town felt like a car-free zone to me. There are just very little parking slots in the centre. There&amp;rsquo;s no traffic lights for pedestrians between Old Town and Telliskivi. You can cross one of Tallinn main roads with an underpass. I did enjoy never stopping to get to work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;telliskivi&#34;&gt;Telliskivi
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#telliskivi&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I spent most of my time in Telliskivi. It&amp;rsquo;s the home of the rising tech and startup scene in Tallinn. There are many (vegan) restaurants to choose for you lunch dates. There&amp;rsquo;s are unique style, which attracts likeminded people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./Telliskivi.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Graffiti in Telliskivi&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;coworking-space-lift99-&#34;&gt;Coworking Space Lift99 🚀
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#coworking-space-lift99-&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lift99 is one of the popular coworking spaces in Tallinn. I liked their idea leaving your shoes at the entrance to change into slippers. Their staffs is always easy to reach and coordinates the weekly/monthly social events for the community. Tea and Coffee are available for all and the internet connection is fast and reliable. I&amp;rsquo;ll come back to this place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./Coworking.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Lift 99 flex desk area&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;public-transport&#34;&gt;Public Transport
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#public-transport&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I used the public transport to get to the city after I arrived at the airport. Super easy, super affordable, there&amp;rsquo;s a tram line which connects the city with the airport. You can buy your ticket as a QR code. These QR codes are scanned at front entry of the tram or bus. All the transport is free for residents though. Theirs smart card functions as validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vegan-community&#34;&gt;Vegan Community
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#vegan-community&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was surprised by the many options for vegans in the city. My favourite restaurant is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.veganrestoran.ee/en&#34;&gt;VEGAN RESTORAN V&lt;/a&gt;. They have small place in the centre of Old Town. Their menu is suitable for everyone, you&amp;rsquo;ll find something. The self-made cakes and smoothies are as tasty as the main courses. Full recommendation. 😍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./restaurant.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Vegan Restaurant V, best restaurant in town.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;beach&#34;&gt;Beach
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#beach&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you left Old Town, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty flat everywhere. I enjoyed having a short run to beach and watching the sunset. ☀️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./beach.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;things-to-do&#34;&gt;Things to Do:
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#things-to-do&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://meremuuseum.ee/lennusadam/en/&#34;&gt;Lennusadam&lt;/a&gt; represents a part of the marine warfare of Tallinn. I walked in a submarine, learned about different types of sea mines and got a general overview of vessels throughout history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./museum.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Lennusadam Seaplane Harbour Museum&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a thing for photography. Visiting the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fotografiska.com/tallinn/en/&#34;&gt;Fotografiska&lt;/a&gt; in Tallinn was a must-see for me. You get through quick quickly but the admission fee was worth it for me. I was astonished the mastery of photography as art can look like. The exhibitions change in every Fotografiska over the year. There&amp;rsquo;s always something new to discover. 📸&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./Fotografika.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo in Fotografiska&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An other museum you could visit are the &lt;a href=&#34;https://kumu.ekm.ee/en/&#34;&gt;Kumu&lt;/a&gt;. If nature is more your thing, have a look at the Jägala waterfall and the national park Lahemaa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I did fall in love with Tallinn. It&amp;rsquo;s a small city which offers everything I could wish for. The long sun hours in June are perfect for long evenings and fantastical experiences in the city.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a Life as Digital Nomad</title>
      <link>https://czyrnik.me/blog/starting-a-life-as-digital-nomad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://czyrnik.me/blog/starting-a-life-as-digital-nomad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Selling almost all your shit, renting Airbnbs for the upcoming months, saying goodbye to your social circle - sounds familiar? Leave your comfort zone, they said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;./challenge_accepted.png&#34;&#34; alt=&#34;Challenge Accepted&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Get on with it!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;starting-a-life-as-digital-nomad&#34;&gt;Starting a Life as Digital Nomad
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#starting-a-life-as-digital-nomad&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;But why the heck should you leave everything behind and sell your shit? Simple. Flexibility, independence and the sense of adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is incredible, when you can call any place your home! But eventually, someone asks you for the first time: &amp;ldquo;Hey, what are you doing for a living?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That feels weird. How do you explain, what you&amp;rsquo;re trying to accomplish right now? &amp;ldquo;I live out of a suitcase and do things on a computer remotely.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s right-on, but neither concrete nor creative. Going into detail on all the online adventures I&amp;rsquo;m having was not the ideal way to answer that question. 🙃&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next follow-up question &amp;ldquo;Where are you living?&amp;rdquo; becomes awkwardly difficult&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;./freedom.png&#34;&#34; alt=&#34;Freedom Everywhere&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Freedom!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being independent of a fixed location is a privileged lifestyle. You do not need to be a highly educated tech person for it, but it is advantageous being one. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to stay within an English-speaking bubble. There is not much of a change. I do appreciate the privilege of being born into a high income country in the middle of Europe more than I used to! Let&amp;rsquo;s see what the upcoming weeks will add to that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-am-i-expecting-from-the-upcoming-months&#34;&gt;What am I expecting from the upcoming months?
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-am-i-expecting-from-the-upcoming-months&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started to get rid of unnecessary possessions a couple of years ago. Ever since, I’ve been trying to own less and focus more on experiences. Going even more digital is the next step of my journey to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Essentialism&#34;&gt;essentialism&lt;/a&gt;. I want to deepen my understanding of central things in life, at least in my own comprehension. Leaving your typical surroundings can be a great kick-start for exciting  changes! 🚀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;./expectations.png&#34;&#34; alt=&#34;Freedom Everywhere&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;U Can&#39;t Touch This 🎵&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;remote-student-life&#34;&gt;Remote Student Life
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#remote-student-life&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting a digital lifestyle as a student is one of the best starting points. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the most flexible periods in life, anyways. Getting to know new people feels easy and natural!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are nearly no serious obstacles to overcome. Most of the study materials are available online. You need to find a table and an internet connection - that&amp;rsquo;s a piece of cake! The Erasmus Student Network (ESN) is one of many ways to get to know new people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, exams still require attendance. So, there are some weeks in the year, which are bound to a specific location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m excited about the next weeks and months! Many new experiences, memories and friendships will be made.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World! :)</title>
      <link>https://czyrnik.me/blog/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://czyrnik.me/blog/hello/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my blog!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad you are here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll keep you updated in the following weeks and months!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you in the next one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my blog! 🙃</title>
      <link>https://czyrnik.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://czyrnik.me/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, I am &lt;strong&gt;Toni&lt;/strong&gt; and I am an electrical engineer with a deep interest in sustainability and green energy. I study in Aachen, Germany. 🇩🇪 I have a strong interest in the development of smart grid technology and its potential to create a more sustainable future. 💚&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./green_future.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo generated with DALL·E 2&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently working at a &lt;a href=&#34;i4k.org&#34;&gt;social startup&lt;/a&gt; that focuses on teaching kids graphic programming. My role is to help match local students with our classes and spread the word about the benefits of our programs. I am proud to be part of an organization that helps to educate young people and inspire the next generation of tech-savvy individuals. 🧑‍💻&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./kids.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo generated with DALL·E 2&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My passion for triathlon and nutrition comes from a desire to promote a healthier lifestyle. I have spent many years studying these topics and have gained a deep understanding of the importance of a balanced approach to both physical activity and nutrition. For me, a combination of rigorous exercise and a nutritious diet is essential. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s competing in a triathlon or making healthier choices in everyday life, I am dedicated to spreading awareness about the benefits of an active lifestyle. Through my knowledge and experience, I hope to inspire others to take a similar approach and live a healthier and happier life. 🏃🏻&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./teddy.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo generated with DALL·E 2&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides green energy, I am passionate about exploring new places and expanding my knowledge. On this blog, I will share my experiences from my travels and what I have learned from my studies. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s highlighting the sustainable practices I come across on my travels or sharing my thoughts on the latest developments in green energy and electrical engineering, I will provide a unique and personal perspective. I hope to use this platform to inspire and educate others, and to connect with like-minded individuals who share my interests. Join me on this journey as I explore the world, continue to learn and grow, and share my passions with you. 🚀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./future.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo generated with DALL·E 2&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for visiting my blog and I hope you find it informative and thought provoking. Please feel free to contact me with any comments or questions. Let&amp;rsquo;s make a difference together! 🗣️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-am-i-doing-now&#34;&gt;What am I doing now?
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-am-i-doing-now&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../now&#34;&gt;See my now page.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
