<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Toni&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://czyrnik.me/blog/</link>
    <description>Toni&#39;s Blog (Blog)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://czyrnik.me/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a Life as Digital Nomad</title>
      <link>https://czyrnik.me/blog/starting-a-life-as-digital-nomad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://czyrnik.me/blog/starting-a-life-as-digital-nomad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Selling almost all your shit, renting Airbnbs for the upcoming months, saying goodbye to your social circle - sounds familiar? Leave your comfort zone, they said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;./challenge_accepted.png&#34;&#34; alt=&#34;Challenge Accepted&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Get on with it!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;starting-a-life-as-digital-nomad&#34;&gt;Starting a Life as Digital Nomad
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#starting-a-life-as-digital-nomad&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;But why the heck should you leave everything behind and sell your shit? Simple. Flexibility, independence and the sense of adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is incredible, when you can call any place your home! But eventually, someone asks you for the first time: &amp;ldquo;Hey, what are you doing for a living?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That feels weird. How do you explain, what you&amp;rsquo;re trying to accomplish right now? &amp;ldquo;I live out of a suitcase and do things on a computer remotely.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s right-on, but neither concrete nor creative. Going into detail on all the online adventures I&amp;rsquo;m having was not the ideal way to answer that question. 🙃&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next follow-up question &amp;ldquo;Where are you living?&amp;rdquo; becomes awkwardly difficult&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;./freedom.png&#34;&#34; alt=&#34;Freedom Everywhere&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Freedom!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being independent of a fixed location is a privileged lifestyle. You do not need to be a highly educated tech person for it, but it is advantageous being one. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to stay within an English-speaking bubble. There is not much of a change. I do appreciate the privilege of being born into a high income country in the middle of Europe more than I used to! Let&amp;rsquo;s see what the upcoming weeks will add to that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-am-i-expecting-from-the-upcoming-months&#34;&gt;What am I expecting from the upcoming months?
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-am-i-expecting-from-the-upcoming-months&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started to get rid of unnecessary possessions a couple of years ago. Ever since, I’ve been trying to own less and focus more on experiences. Going even more digital is the next step of my journey to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Essentialism&#34;&gt;essentialism&lt;/a&gt;. I want to deepen my understanding of central things in life, at least in my own comprehension. Leaving your typical surroundings can be a great kick-start for exciting  changes! 🚀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;./expectations.png&#34;&#34; alt=&#34;Freedom Everywhere&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;U Can&#39;t Touch This 🎵&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;remote-student-life&#34;&gt;Remote Student Life
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#remote-student-life&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting a digital lifestyle as a student is one of the best starting points. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the most flexible periods in life, anyways. Getting to know new people feels easy and natural!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are nearly no serious obstacles to overcome. Most of the study materials are available online. You need to find a table and an internet connection - that&amp;rsquo;s a piece of cake! The Erasmus Student Network (ESN) is one of many ways to get to know new people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, exams still require attendance. So, there are some weeks in the year, which are bound to a specific location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m excited about the next weeks and months! Many new experiences, memories and friendships will be made.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World! :)</title>
      <link>https://czyrnik.me/blog/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://czyrnik.me/blog/hello/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my blog!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad you are here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll keep you updated in the following weeks and months!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you in the next one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
