<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on Toni&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://czyrnik.me/categories/travel/</link>
    <description>Toni&#39;s Blog (Travel)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://czyrnik.me/categories/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Nomad Experience in Riga</title>
      <link>https://czyrnik.me/blog/nomad-riga/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://czyrnik.me/blog/nomad-riga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;welcome-to-the-baltics---riga-edition&#34;&gt;Welcome to the Baltics - Riga Edition
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#welcome-to-the-baltics---riga-edition&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was an easy bus ride between Tallinn and Riga. My Airbnb was near the main railway station, a few minutes walk. Riga felt more chaotic than Tallinn for the first few minutes. There are more people, cars and buses. 🚎&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./city_aerial.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Aerial Shot by Gilly&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;old-town&#34;&gt;Old Town
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#old-town&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Riga&amp;rsquo;s Old Town is a UNESCO World Heritage Site. The cobbled streets are lined with medieval buildings, many of which have been beautifully restored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./old_town.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Old Town Vibes by Jacques Bopp&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the main highlights of the Old Town is the Town Hall Square, which is home to the impressive Riga Town Hall. This Gothic-style building was built in the 14th century and now houses the Riga City Council. The Town Hall Square is surrounded by other notable buildings, such as the House of the Blackheads and the St. Peter&amp;rsquo;s Church. You can take a guided tour of the Town Hall to learn more about its history and architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./townhall.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Town Hall Square by Martin Kleppe&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The St. Peter&amp;rsquo;s Church is one of the largest medieval churches in the Baltic region. Built in the 13th century, it is a mixture of Gothic and Baroque styles. You can take a guided tour of the cathedral to learn more about its history and admire its impressive stained glass windows and frescoes. 🔔&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./cathedral.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;St. Peter&#39;s Church by Artem Makarov&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Old Town is a great place to explore on foot. You can stroll along the cobbled streets and admire the colorful buildings and street art. The Old Town is full of shops, cafes and restaurants where you can enjoy traditional Latvian food and drinks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vegan-community&#34;&gt;Vegan Community
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#vegan-community&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Riga has a thriving vegan community, with several restaurants and cafes catering to this lifestyle. Many of these places offer delicious and healthy food options, such as salads, smoothies, and raw desserts. 💚&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./kozy_eats.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Kozy Eats by Kozy Eats&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it is less common to be vegan in Riga. I cooked a lot during my stay. 👨‍🍳&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;population&#34;&gt;Population
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#population&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the collapse of the Soviet Union in 1991, Latvia regained its independence and began the process of transition to a market economy. This led to significant changes in the demographics of the city&amp;rsquo;s population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 1990s, Riga&amp;rsquo;s population declined due to emigration, mainly of the Russian-speaking population. The city&amp;rsquo;s population fell from around 900,000 in the early 1990s to around 700,000 in the late 1990s. This trend was driven by the economic and political instability in the country during this period and the desire of many Russian-speaking residents to return to their home country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./Riga_plot.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Population Trend in Riga&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city&amp;rsquo;s economy improved and more people moved to the city to work and study. EU accession in 2004 helped to attract more investment and business opportunities to Riga. Outside the city centre, many commercial spaces are unoccupied. Walking through the outer streets can sometimes feel sad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The streets are full of cars, even though the city has lost almost a third of its population. It&amp;rsquo;s always busy in Riga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;public-transport&#34;&gt;Public Transport
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#public-transport&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Riga has a well-developed public transport system that includes buses, trams and trolleybuses. Buses run frequently and can take you to most destinations in Riga. The tram system has several lines running through the city centre and suburbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public transport in Riga is affordable, with a one-way ticket costing around two euros (valid for one hour) and a day ticket costing around four euros (valid for 24 hours).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are travelling by train, you can use the official app (Pasažieru vilciens) to buy your tickets. The stations outside the city can be minimalist though. 😊&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./beach_train.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Train Station near the beach&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;beach&#34;&gt;Beach
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#beach&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Riga&amp;rsquo;s beach is not the most popular among tourists, but it is worth a visit. The beach is located in Jurmala, a coastal town about 30 minutes from the city centre. 🚂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed taking the train from Riga Central Station to one of the stops along the beach. Personally, time on the beach gives me an instant holiday feeling. 🤓&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./beach1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Beach near Riga&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beach is long and wide, with fine white sand and clear blue water. There are many beach bars and restaurants serving delicious food and drinks. It is the perfect place to relax and enjoy the sun and sea. ☀️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./beach2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Beach near Riga&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;parks&#34;&gt;Parks
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#parks&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Riga has several beautiful parks, perfect for a relaxing stroll or a picnic. The largest and most popular park is Mežaparks, located on the banks of the Daugava River. The park has a lake, a playground and several monuments. Another popular park is Esplanade Park, located in the heart of the city, with a music pavilion, fountain and several statues. The park is a great place to relax and enjoy the fresh air. There are many other small parks and gardens throughout the city, such as the Riga Botanical Garden and Ziedoņdārzs Park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./boat_park.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Tourist Boat in Esplanade Park&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to go to the park on hot, sunny days. Combined with a light breeze, it&amp;rsquo;s the perfect summer day in the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./water_park.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Esplanade Park&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Riga is a beautiful and affordable city. My favorite place in Riga was the beach.I&amp;rsquo;d prefer Tallinn to Riga. Although Riga is the bigger city with more opportunities.🙃&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./me.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Me in Riga, June 2022&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote Studying and Working in Tallinn</title>
      <link>https://czyrnik.me/blog/nomad-tallinn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://czyrnik.me/blog/nomad-tallinn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;welcome-to-the-baltics&#34;&gt;Welcome to the Baltics
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#welcome-to-the-baltics&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, I chose Tallinn as the first destination as a digital nomad. Tallinn - the tiny capital many never heard of. I think it&amp;rsquo;s one of the most underrated cities in Europe. 🇪🇺&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estonia is the country with the most digital government in Europe. Their ID cards provide digital access for signatures, voting, medical records and submitting tax claims. You can even start your first business digitally. But there are things you need to do in person: marriage, divorce and a credit for properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;IT education is important in Estonia. All children start learning about algorithms and coding at the age of seven. It&amp;rsquo;s designed to be preparation for the digital age.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./Old town Entrance.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Small Street in Tallinn Old Town by 66 north&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun Fact: When you walk around the city, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice the lokal coffeeshops &amp;ldquo;Reval&amp;rdquo;. That&amp;rsquo;s the original name of the city until 1918. The name changed to Tallinn with the independence of Estonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reval was a significant trade hub in Europe during the 14th and 16th centuries. Today, the old town of Tallinn is one of the best-preserved medieval cities and is classified as a UNESCO World Heritage Site. You get a glimpse of the former medieval fortress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tallinn was occupied by the German until end of World War 1. Followed by the occupation by the Red Army during World War 2 in 1940. Nazi Germany occupied the city from 1941 to 1944. But Soviet occupation was quickly reestablished until 1991. Tallinn became the capital of an independent country once again in August 1991. 🎉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;population&#34;&gt;Population
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#population&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tallinn experienced an extensive influx of Russian immigrants during the Soviet occupation (1944-1991). Whole new city districts were developed like Lasnamäe,T which became the most populous district of Tallinn in the 1980s. &lt;em&gt;Today, about 50 % of the inhabits speak Estonian and about 46 % speak Russian as their native language.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./plot.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Inhabitants in Estonia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;old-town&#34;&gt;Old Town
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#old-town&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was lucky to live in the middle of the city. My apartment was next to the town hall square. Many tourists arrive by ferry and bus for day trips. Consequently, the streets can get crowded. But the early mornings and late nights are comparatively quiet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./Old town.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Small streets in Old Town by 
Nikola Johnny Mirkovic&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the Russian embassy was always guarded by at least one Estonian police car. Estonias do support the Ukrainians in the war. 🇺🇦&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./embassy.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Posters in front of the Russian embassy&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old Town felt like a car-free zone to me. There are just very little parking slots in the centre. There&amp;rsquo;s no traffic lights for pedestrians between Old Town and Telliskivi. You can cross one of Tallinn main roads with an underpass. I did enjoy never stopping to get to work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;telliskivi&#34;&gt;Telliskivi
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#telliskivi&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I spent most of my time in Telliskivi. It&amp;rsquo;s the home of the rising tech and startup scene in Tallinn. There are many (vegan) restaurants to choose for you lunch dates. There&amp;rsquo;s are unique style, which attracts likeminded people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./Telliskivi.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Graffiti in Telliskivi&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;coworking-space-lift99-&#34;&gt;Coworking Space Lift99 🚀
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#coworking-space-lift99-&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lift99 is one of the popular coworking spaces in Tallinn. I liked their idea leaving your shoes at the entrance to change into slippers. Their staffs is always easy to reach and coordinates the weekly/monthly social events for the community. Tea and Coffee are available for all and the internet connection is fast and reliable. I&amp;rsquo;ll come back to this place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./Coworking.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Lift 99 flex desk area&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;public-transport&#34;&gt;Public Transport
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#public-transport&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I used the public transport to get to the city after I arrived at the airport. Super easy, super affordable, there&amp;rsquo;s a tram line which connects the city with the airport. You can buy your ticket as a QR code. These QR codes are scanned at front entry of the tram or bus. All the transport is free for residents though. Theirs smart card functions as validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vegan-community&#34;&gt;Vegan Community
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#vegan-community&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was surprised by the many options for vegans in the city. My favourite restaurant is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.veganrestoran.ee/en&#34;&gt;VEGAN RESTORAN V&lt;/a&gt;. They have small place in the centre of Old Town. Their menu is suitable for everyone, you&amp;rsquo;ll find something. The self-made cakes and smoothies are as tasty as the main courses. Full recommendation. 😍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./restaurant.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Vegan Restaurant V, best restaurant in town.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;beach&#34;&gt;Beach
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#beach&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you left Old Town, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty flat everywhere. I enjoyed having a short run to beach and watching the sunset. ☀️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./beach.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;things-to-do&#34;&gt;Things to Do:
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#things-to-do&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://meremuuseum.ee/lennusadam/en/&#34;&gt;Lennusadam&lt;/a&gt; represents a part of the marine warfare of Tallinn. I walked in a submarine, learned about different types of sea mines and got a general overview of vessels throughout history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./museum.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Lennusadam Seaplane Harbour Museum&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a thing for photography. Visiting the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fotografiska.com/tallinn/en/&#34;&gt;Fotografiska&lt;/a&gt; in Tallinn was a must-see for me. You get through quick quickly but the admission fee was worth it for me. I was astonished the mastery of photography as art can look like. The exhibitions change in every Fotografiska over the year. There&amp;rsquo;s always something new to discover. 📸&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;./Fotografika.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; height=auto width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo in Fotografiska&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An other museum you could visit are the &lt;a href=&#34;https://kumu.ekm.ee/en/&#34;&gt;Kumu&lt;/a&gt;. If nature is more your thing, have a look at the Jägala waterfall and the national park Lahemaa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I did fall in love with Tallinn. It&amp;rsquo;s a small city which offers everything I could wish for. The long sun hours in June are perfect for long evenings and fantastical experiences in the city.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
